Translation: Sixteen Jihuang cuminplus, a langlang pear, Yang Kai, honest bean paste bag
Proofreading: Mahsele Zhang HollaBella 16
Shaft\Pressure: Machsel Zhang
Welcome to follow Sina Weibo @马赫塞勒张 to get the video download address with embedded Chinese and English subtitles and translator annotations
The translations used in this subtitle when referring to the original text of the "Bible" are based on the "Mandarin Chinese Union Version" ("God" version)
The Psychological Significance of "Bible" Story Seventh Lecture: Walking with God——Noah and the Ark by Jordan B. Peterson
thank you all
I took a look today
This series of lectures has now been broadcasted over 1 million online
Pretty amazing
Or they are only viewed 1 million times
This is also possible
Okay, let's go directly to the topic
I think last week
There is too little content related to the Bible
Let me summarize what was laid out last time
Set up a frame for tonight’s discussion
I basically describe this picture in detail for everyone
It took me a long time to imagine
About 25 years ago
This may be why this picture looks so primitive
Seriously, I put my 486 computer
Run to the limit to make this picture
This picture is
A manifestation of the life prototype situation
These prototype situations
It's true no matter when and where
So you can think of them as
Description of the essential characteristics of human experience
This is not the same as reality
Because you can divide reality into subjective and objective elements
This is effective
But these manifestations will not be so distinguished
They believe that human experience is an integral part of reality
We also experienced this
So we just follow this
This basically means
We always exist in an incomplete structure
Part of this structure is biological
Partly social and cultural
Part of it was passed on to us by our ancestors
As far as the underlying architecture is concerned, the same is true from the practicality
Psychologically
This is also true for the content we learn autonomously
Including, for example, our ability to use language
Words and sentences used
Also formed through communication and interaction
Mutual understanding
In terms of prototype, this system is always old and corrupt
It's dead because
It is constructed by the dead
It is rotten because
Things will always fall apart spontaneously
And the fact that people don’t establish goals and directions
Accelerated the process of degeneration
I think you need to pay attention to some things
People always stand aside
Wait to see when these problems disappear by themselves
I mean to say
Young people always have many reasons for the status quo of things
Feel cynical
Always be like this
I think in this view
Concepts such as patriarchal society are very useful
The social structure is corrupt and incomplete
Is a prototype fact
this means
To some extent your whole life
Have to deal with it
This is a constant fact of existence itself
So the incomplete social structure we live in
Or even biological structure
Feel angry and frustrated
I feel all this is for myself
But the worst
I feel all this is against myself
Is a misunderstanding of human existence
Because of what you are given and where you live
Is degraded and corrupt and needs to be corrected
Always like this
This fact is not difficult to accept
Because it also has positive factors
That is
At least you were given something
Instead of nothing
And didn't give you pure hell
Because especially in our western culture
Many things are working well
There are many things to be grateful for
Even a broken machine
Not completely hopeless
It didn't want to
every moment
All make you trapped in pain and destruction
It can easily become like that
Because many societies are like that
We have not lived in a
A society that is so corrupted beyond imagination
This fact is very grateful
So we all live in a broken structure
We are also responsible for its incompleteness because
We haven’t been doing our best to fix it
You might say this is a basic
People always ask what is the meaning of life
What they really want to ask is what is the positive meaning of life
Because like we said
The negative meaning of life is somewhat self-evident
However, the positive meaning is in
Realize that the siege you live in needs to be repaired
Then ran to do something
For example, fill in the gap and repair the wall
The structure you live in
Be as safe and productive as possible
You do not lack the opportunity to do so
You can do it in your heart
You can do this in your room
You can do this in your family
You can do this in your community
If you do this thing well on these levels
You can set the goal higher
There will always be challenges
what is interesting is
Inside this incomplete structure
Always embedded with a series of challenges
Because of its incompleteness
Maybe even because of its rotten nature
It is calling you to a heroic adventure
Potential answer
To take a heroic adventure is to fix the roadblock
Repair the city
You can always do
No matter what kind of environment you are in
There will always be some around you
Something wrong
Things that have not been properly arranged
You can fix things if you want
We are going to talk tonight
One of the things is
If you take that attitude
What you should do is make the world a better place
No matter where you are no matter what you do
In fact, after you did
The world will get better
Wherever you are in various forms
We as a race
More or as a different individual
Rarely realize this
It will not be used as a proposition often
This surprised me
I experienced an interesting thing one day
I went to eat at the Keg steakhouse
Because I am allergic to many foods
This restaurant treats people with food allergies very carefully
The waiter took me to my seat
He said he has been watching my lecture
I often hear this
He is very happy about it
He said he had been in the past two months
I have been promoted twice in this restaurant
Because he watched my lecture
I really think his experience is very moving
You might say he is just a waiter
There is nothing special about bravery
I disagree
Because i don't care where you are
You can do your work to the extreme
I really mean this
You can accept a job
Then turn it into a complete nightmare
Or you can act like a civilized human
And realized that no matter where you are
There is a variety of variety on hand
Unfinished things
And you will take it seriously
you can say
"I just happened to be a waiter in this restaurant"
"This is not the job I expected."
He is a young man
"Maybe this is not where I belong."
"But it's not useless, it's a rich environment"
"I can make it much better if I want."
"I can get along well with my colleagues"
"Don't just talk about them behind their backs"
"I can treat my customers well"
"If there is a chance to show up in front of me, I will seize it"
"I can pay attention to what is happening around me"
That guy said he did that
Things got better
He has a higher position than three months ago
How long is three months
This is a good track
Is going uphill
This is what you really want
I think an uphill road is better than
Better to be in a good situation
Because it can really make your life meaningful
You know soberly that you are moving towards a place
That place is better than where you are now
If you understand
What you are doing and your tendency to do it
It would be better if there is direct causality
I have received many letters like this
Most of them are written to me by young men, although not all
They said "I have been listening to your lessons"
"I made up my mind to try to take the responsibility of life."
"I stopped doing those stupid things
"Those stupid things I know I shouldn't do"
"I started doing those
"Not stupid, I know what I should do"
Actually it's pretty obvious whether you should do it
If you think about it
But even if they are obvious
People don’t do these things
Then they wrote to me saying
"You can't believe how much change this has brought me."
They are very excited about it
I was also very excited when I received such a letter
I really don’t compare to receiving such a letter
Better experience
Because seeing the less good things replaced by better things
This is really great
I think this is an inconclusive question
I really believe this is an inconclusive question
"If we are determined to do something
"How far can we make them better?"
Some of the stories we discussed
Especially the story of Cain and Abel
Is the analysis of this problem
This is a compelling analysis
It appears so early in these texts
Such a basic story
It basically says
There are two modes of behavior in the world
One is that you take it rightly
The responsibility to live
And then make the necessary sacrifices
So everything can flourish
The other is the path of hatred
Painful renunciation, killing and extinction
It seems to me exactly like this
So if the positive way is beckoning you if you can notice it
If you can really lower your head and humbly notice it
Carl Jung once said
"Modern people cannot see God
"Because they refuse to condescend to look at it."
That's a sentence I like very much
People look down on
The opportunity that appeared before them
It doesn't make sense
It is the majesty of being that appears before you
This is what appeared in front of you
It is endlessly complex and full of potential
You have no reason to assume where you are now
As a starting point
I know some people have terrible lives
Their situation is completely beyond the tolerance of ordinary people
But i also know
Even in that situation
Can be made worse by your worst attitude
I am very sure of that
So anyway you are in that situation
You are in a damaged structure
You yourself are a damaged structure
But it still has a few walls
You are not fed to lions every day as food
This is a good thing
You can rush out like a hero and magically
To face those
The chaos that constantly endangers your structure
You can free something by doing this
You can learn something to make yourself stronger
This is another aspect
Because it affects your composition
It’s what you encounter when you voluntarily face the unknown
The more you voluntarily face the unknown
The more you will grow
The more you grow, the more things you can meet
You are more and more able to face the unknown
Then re-establish order
From the potential of being
Summon the right order
Gosh, do you have to think about it
Why don't you do this
Even if you can do it
This is an endless mystery
To a certain extent, this truth is also covered in
In the story of Adam and Eve
Adam became self-aware and self-aware
And feel ashamed of myself
He considers himself a lowly creature
People will think so for countless reasons
Because we are full of defects
So Adam avoided God
I think this is the answer to this puzzle
People do not aim for the highest good
Because they are ashamed of themselves
Their weaknesses and shortcomings
This is not the only reason
There is also a desire to avoid responsibility
And also all those negative motives
Like resentment and hatred
And the expectation of making things worse
I don’t want everyone to think about the relaxed side
Almost like this
So it’s okay if you are in a not so good place
If all you want to do is put where you are
become better
As a clinical psychologist I know one thing
It’s just that you can’t believe how powerful a bit of progress can be
You can do a calculation like a cumulative interest rate
If you can make your life a tenth better every week
In two or three years
You can get to a much better place than you are now
Reminiscence
If you insist on ten or twenty years
Especially if you are still young
You start cheering up earlier
Then start to solve the problems you can solve
You can transform your life incredibly
In terms of human possibilities
God knows what its upper limit is
We are magical creatures
When we really cheer up
And no longer just run at our 10% capacity
So you should do
Things are not what they should be
This thing at least gives you something to do
Maybe still something great
Because the suffering and troubles are endless
They haunt the world
So you can improve the world
The utility of this and its own meaning are self-evident
This also makes me
Curious about things like nihilism and despair
I understand these emotions
I understand them deeply
And the mentality of intellectuals accompanying it
But they are off the point to some extent
Because there are so many things to do
You just need to open your eyes
Look at them and decide
What will you really do
You might think
Things i can influence
Too trivial, no need to do it
But if you do it, it won’t always be trivial
Not at all
Besides, I didn’t think it was trivial at first
I don’t think any one thing is trivial
My life experience tells me
Everything I did pays off
It doesn’t have to be returned to me in the way I expected
This is totally different
But if you really make up your mind to do something
Even if it goes off
Its result is not what I expected
But the overall result will be good in the long run
All conquerable new areas are a step forward
New fields will never be exhausted
We are surrounded by the unknown
We are surrounded by our own ignorance
We can choose to continuously advance to the chaotic realm
Or we can reshape these pathological orders
This is the secret of legitimate being
So when you face chaos
You can think of yourself as a
Individuals who have the ability to overcome chaos despite their defects
Not to mention the danger of doing this is another matter
Because of the fact that you are fragile
Is the premise of your heroism
Because if you are not vulnerable
Then do a difficult thing itself
There is no bravery, is it?
If you can't be hurt or knocked down
Or end in failure
So where are these hardworking warriors?
That fragility must be deeply rooted in courage
Not a reason to escape
In fact the opposite
So what should you do
You integrate and revitalize the city
Maybe change back to what you want
So that it becomes practical, efficient and beautiful
People can open branches there
It makes people feel
The unbearable disaster of existence itself
Becomes worth experiencing
That's what you should be determined to do
It's not impossible
Then you didn’t just repair the city
You turned yourself into a
Repairman who keeps repairing the city
That's even better, that's your ultimate goal
Your goal is not only to repair the city
Still have to turn yourself into a
A repairman who can keep repairing the city
There is no reason why this kind of thing shouldn't happen
The more such things happen, the better
There is a dark line in the story of the flood
Is the fact that the city has become corrupt
Because people don’t make heroic efforts
Or they did the opposite endeavor
Committed a completely destructive behavior
This is another thing worth thinking about
If you think about your own life
You can say to people
"You have to tell the truth and be a good person"
This is obviously a cliché
Also because it's a cliché
So not convincing
But you can take it apart to see
Practice this sentence in a less old-fashioned way
For example, you can look at this sentence more modestly
Maybe you can't tell the truth because
You don't know what the truth is
But there is one thing you can do
You can stop telling lies that you know
You might say how do I know which words are false
To answer this question requires a philosophy of truth
Have a long talk
Let’s not delve into this question
Because in a sense this is not the point we are going to talk about now
The problem is that there are always times in your life
You know what you are saying is not true
It’s a lie
You use it to manipulate yourself
Or manipulate others or the world
And you still think that you can retreat without being held accountable
This is demonic arrogance
In fact, this arrogant prototype is shown in
In the mythical image of the devil Satan
Satan is the ones who think they can
People who distort the structure of reality without paying the price
Prototype thought element
You can't think of anything more arrogant than this
You really think you can distort the facts
Then this will bring you benefits
Won't you receive any retribution?
Everyone knows it won't work
Back to the topic at the beginning
you know
According to the rules of the game you are playing
sometimes
You are violating those rules of the game
The first thing we are talking about is
Tell the truth or take responsibility
They just mean
Don't cheat in the game of your choice
This is a good starting point
Then you will start to sort out your life
So how does the flood relate to this
We live in a corrupt structure
We are corrupt as independent individuals
Part of the spoilage is just accident
Things just fall apart like this
But another part of the corruption is because
Our goals are often not positive but negative
The flood story is a very clear warning
The warning is if your goal is negative enough
Then there are enough people like this
Everything will go backwards
Like the chaos at the beginning of time
Probably like this
The appearance of the universe in mythology is chaos versus order
It can be said that order is above and chaos always hides below
Chaos can burst and order can collapse
And you can plunge into chaos
Chaos is a mixed potential
The way to disrupt order and make chaos rise
As depicted in the flood story
Was parasitic on your father's body
This is a mythical theme
And cannibalized his body without gratitude
Never thought of compensating for what I have been asking for
The warning in the flood story is not to do this for long
Because things will get so bad you can't imagine
That will happen to you
Will happen in your family
Also happen in your social group
This kind of thing happened to people time and time again in history
It's kind of interesting
After the story of Cain and Abel is over
In the story of Adam and Eve, evil soon came to the world
And accompanied by the awakening of self-awareness
Evil is the knowledge of good and evil in this story
Is the ability to hurt others
Have a clear understanding of what you are doing
Of course Cain immediately took this to the extreme
He destroyed his beloved with that ability
He did his best to destroy the divine ideal
His younger brother named Abel is favored by God
Cain destroyed him
At the end of that chapter Cain said to God
The punishment he received was beyond his capacity
I think the reason is
Once you destroy your ideals, where will you be
What are you left
You can't go where there is no room for improvement
When there is no room for improvement, there will be a lot of fall
Milton in "Paradise Lost"
When describing the nature of hell from a psychological perspective
Came up with a very good idea
Your depth in hell is your distance from the "good"
This way of understanding is also very good
If you destroy your own ideals
With jealousy and resentment
With the desire to defeat the person you want to be
You will fall into a situation no different from hell
The story of the Bible is unfolded by Cain
Then the flood
Cain adopted a way of being that is opposed to being itself
At least as opposed to being positive
He did it voluntarily
Fully aware of what you are doing
When this way of being affects the entire social structure
The end result is
God stepped back and said
"The whole thing got so bad
"All we can do is destroy this."
This is not a joke, this is how things are
In this series of stories
There is a very scary thing
And I believe in its authenticity
I am independent of my analysis of myths
Aware of this
I checked China under Mao Zedong in the Soviet Union
And what happened in places like Nazi Germany
Those who have the most keen insight into these societies
How those absolute disasters happened
Those who are most interested
All said the same thing
It is rooted in the degeneration of the individuals that make up this society
You hear them say "people just obey orders"
No, this explanation is simply not tenable
"If people resist, they will be punished."
This is a bit true
But not as good as people might think
Especially at the beginning of the process
It's more people's decision
Each of them
Turn a blind eye to disasters and participate in lies
This distorts the whole society
They turned towards
The closest place you can think of to hell
Especially in Nazi Germany
Including the above three places
Like the Chinese Soviet Union in the Mao era
The scary thing in "Genesis" is
They speak very clearly
Your moral degradation will largely lead to
Degeneration of the entire universe
You would say i want my life to be meaningful
People say that, but is that true?
Do you really want to make your life meaningful
You think people will use a bit of nihilism
To escape that special realization
I think people have always done this
Recognize that it is too heavy
But we are connected
This is the weakness caused by our strong communication skills
Of course the chain reaction of our personal behavior
May be far beyond the limits of our current consciousness
I think people know this too
They are a kind of "I know
"But I don’t want to realize that I know."
In other words, people know their specific manifestations
People can feel them
People have emotional reactions to these things
But refused to make them clear
Because they don't want to know
When you do or haven’t done things to yourself
When feeling guilty and ashamed
I know this can become uncontrollable
This is usually because you have a small distorted self
Want the worst result
One thing Jung said about shadows is
That’s Jung’s famous theory that everyone has a dark side
And the dark side needs to be integrated and aware
The dark side of humanity will spread all the way to hell
This is the interesting thing about reading Jung's works
He said exactly what he meant
This is not a metaphor
Partly twisted to oppose beings
Is consistent with part of the conscious universe
Your goal is to make everything as bad as possible
Realizing this can be very shocking
This is part of the reason why people don’t want to realize it
People will keep a certain distance from it
It’s like admitting to be a guard of a Nazi concentration camp
This exercise is very useful
It's entirely possible that you used to be such a guard
And most likely you are still
If you don't think so
Then there is more reason to assume
You are powerless to resist when temptation really comes to you
If you don’t think guarding this position is a temptation
Then you really don't understand human nature
You didn't even touch the door
If this is not a temptation
There won't be so many people doing this
And many people have done this, nothing new
The seriousness of the story of "Genesis" develops very, very fast
Serious depth is the ultimate prototype
How serious you can be
The story of Noah and the Flood unfolds in a fragmented way
I believe these clips are part of a longer story
And we only have fragments of this long story
And this long story is also part of other stories
This is how the story begins
"When there are more people in the world,
"When the daughter was born again" (Genesis 6:1)
"The sons of God see the beauty of human women
"Just choose and marry as your wife" (Genesis 6:2)
There are two ways of looking at the past
You can see this in our political environment
On the more conservative end of the political spectrum
People think the past is the place of great people
Heroes of the past
Created our current environment
The left may be more concerned about
Corruption that has lasted for centuries
Both views are correct
You can say that there were many great heroes in the past
They established our model of being
You can imagine the two as compound creatures if you want
This is a very reasonable way of thinking
You can also think about the centuries
The accumulation of corruption and evil
Both views are reflected in these lines of Scripture
"The sons of God (the heroes)
"Women who see people are beautiful
"Just choose and marry as your wife" (Genesis 6:2)
Then this statement is a bit illogical
"The Lord says
"Man is natural
"My spirit will not live in him forever
"However, his life can reach one hundred and twenty years" (Gen 6:3)
I studied various interpretations of this section
Because it doesn’t seem to be clearly connected to the previous section
Its exact meaning is not obvious
The first line is about the heroes of the past
The second line means slow
The way of human existence is corrupt
As far as God is concerned, one of the consequences of this situation is
In some cases
The divine spirit will not fight against humans
This means that in some cases
Let me put it this way I think there is no better explanation than this
This means the divine impulse for good
Will leave you because of what you have done
The second thing to consider is
Maybe due to human degradation
The limited life span is not obvious
Our spirit only exists for a limited time
It in a strange way
Intertwined with human moral guilt
This is contrary to the concept of great men in the past
Then the story goes back to the point of view of the great man
"At that time there were great men on the ground
"Later the sons of God
"Women who have sex with men have children
"That is the famous person of ancient heroism" (Genesis 6:4)
This is the end of the sequence fragment is very fragmented
But you can see that there are two narratives behind this
One of them is like this
Corruption is always lurking
Even the nature of the great men of the past is the same
This led to God’s refusal to show grace and the fall of mankind
Pave the way for the story of Noah and the flood
"Jehovah sees that people are sinful on earth
"Everything you think about all day is evil" (Genesis 6:5)
When I was a child, I really didn't like going to church
I went to a very gentle church
It is a united church
It’s not even a church now
It can be said to be too mild
One of the reasons I don’t like
The pastor was chattering about the sinful nature of man
I don't think it's right
Partly because i don't understand the meaning
Partly because of its self-flagellation
Seems unattractive
I don’t know if there are any ways to make self-flagellation attractive
There are some mechanical and fake things that I don’t like
I did more thinking in the following years
I started to understand
Let people take the evil
Clearly and consciously
Putting it at the forefront of imagination has practical meaning
I think I mentioned it to you last week
A short section of Mesopotamian culture
It’s about the emperor and the traditions of the New Year holiday
People would take the emperor out of the city wall and strip off his dragon suit
Make him an ordinary person
Then people will humiliate him in the ceremony
Questioned him what happened in the past year
Why haven't you become the majestic incarnation of Marduk
Marduk is the god of Mesopotamia
He created order from chaos
The emperor should sit down and think
"Well, I am an emperor, I should behave well."
"You have to perform well."
"But it's likely that I lack in many aspects
"The missing part happens to be very important
"Because I'm starring in this whole ceremony."
"I should be very, very clear
"How did I fail my ideals"
I want to say that in institutionalized Christianity
This is a horn that is constantly degrading
That’s actually the Christian view
There are thousands of ways
Stop you from being everything you want to be
It shouldn't be a whip to knock you down
Although it might have whipped your pride
The pride that prevents you from seeing your shortcomings
It's more like a horn to the opposite side
It's like saying it's enough to stop
You can do better than now
It will be of great benefit to you and to others
But it won’t be good if you continue to break your own rules
Because as I said
If you start playing this game
You should at least follow the rules of the game
If you observe yourself
It's a little scary
But if you pay attention
I will find myself lying
I was in my 20s when I first realized this
I am a smart person and I was very proud of it
I was also a small man back then
The seat was adjusted forward when going to school
I was not tall when I enrolled
So I am very short in the class
I am also very talkative
At this point, everyone may be surprised
I'm still a bit provocative
So I am often bullied
After all, no one is immune
My weapon is to talk
This is a very effective weapon although it can backfire
Because you know
If you talk so much to a rough big man
They will probably start heavy manual roughing
That kind of thing often happens to me
But I am very proud that I have some intellectual advantages
At that time when I was in my 20s
I started to realize the danger
I started reading "Paradise Lost" by Milton
And began to understand the dangers of intelligence
In my opinion, the danger of intelligence lies in
It can easily lead to arrogance and arrogance
It’s easy to be obsessed with your own creations
In fact that is Lucifer
In "Paradise Lost" that is Lucifer
Lucifer is brilliant
He is obsessed with his creation
I think there is nothing outside of my thinking
This is a totalitarian mentality, isn't it
"We have an overall system
"Know how everything works"
"We will implement
"So paradise on earth is realized"
This is a totalitarian mentality
Related to intellectual arrogance
Then another thing happened
I noticed this problem myself
And start to understand what that means
I also started to understand
There are other things in life besides intelligence
Too much
I was crazy about smoking and drinking
The weight is almost 60 kg
My body is not that good
I had a lot of things to do when I was a graduate student
Come to cheer yourself up
At the same time I tried to figure it out
Why is the world wrong like this
This can be seen in the epitome of the Cold War
And what role will i play in it
If there is any role
What role will each of us play in it
I didn’t work long in a prison at that time
I work with a crazy psychologist
He often adds jokes to multiple choice tests
He is a very weird guy
But i like his class very much
He taught a course on "creativity"
Also a prison psychologist
He is a weird guy
I don't know why he favors me
Maybe it's because I'm also weird
He invited me many times
Go with him to the highest security prison in Edmonton
I went
It was a very interesting experience
Because i want to figure it out
Individual behavior for the group
What is the role of the abnormal state
Reasons like this
I went and met a little guy shorter than me
I grew taller then
He is a pretty harmless guy
Then I came to the gym
The prison looks like a high school
It looks really like to me
There are all heavy lifting guys
Everyone is wicked
I remember someone with tattoos all over
There is a huge scar in the middle of the chest
Looks like someone was injured with an axe
I stood there in the weird cloak that I often wear
I bought it in Portugal and paired it with boots
Like the cloak of Sherlock Holmes in the 1890s
It really looks like the clothing of the 1890s
Because the small village is on the mountain
Surrounded by city wall villagers selling these things
I think they haven’t changed the style since the end of the 19th century
So i think it's pretty cool
I just wore it like this
This may not be the most conservative dress
If you are going to the highest security prison
I'm in the gym anyway
The psychologist left
God knows what's going on, he's such a weird person
Everyone gathered around
They want to exchange my prison clothes for my cloak
I can hardly refuse this request
I really don't know what to do
Then this little guy spoke
He said the psychologist asked me to take you away
Similar words
I just thought "Okay
"This little guy is better than those big guys."
We walked out of the gym
Go through a few "school gates" to the playground
We wandered around and he started chatting with me
He looks like a harmless guy
Then the psychologist appeared at the door
Motion us to go back
It's a relief
I walked into his office
He said, "Do you know the man who walked with you on the playground?"
I said yes"
He said, "One night, that man kidnapped two policemen."
"Let them kneel down"
"The two beg him to make a living."
"He shot the back of the two heads."
I thought "good guy"
You see, the interesting thing about this is
He looks pretty harmless, right
You think someone like him would do this kind of thing
Let's put it this way, it must be completely different from you
Certainly not a harmless looking guy
Do you think that person would be
Half-werewolf and half-vampire look
Then you immediately know that he is a cold-blooded killer
but not
He is such an insignificant little person
But if you give him a revolver
Of course he is not so harmless
I thought a lot about this
What is the relationship between harmless and dangerous
Then something happened
I met another person there
In a week or two
I heard he and his friend caught the other guy
Smashed the man's left leg with a lead pipe
Just like that
They did it because they thought that man was an informer
Maybe he really is
My reaction was different that time
I was not just shocked or frightened
Although I was really scared
What I think is how can you do it
Because I don't think I can do it
I think myself and those people
There are essential differences
So I spent two weeks trying to figure out
Under what conditions would i do this
What kind of psychological change do I experience
To do that
It can be said that it is a kind of meditation training
After only ten days I found out
I can not only do
And it's much easier than I expected
I've been here since
And the wall between the "shadow" described by Jung
Began to fall apart
That's also useful
Because I started to treat myself as a different individual
Because I didn’t realize it before
I thought I was a good person
Naturally, there is no reason to think badly about yourself
Unless you really do your best to be a good person
Otherwise you are not a good person
Really not being a good person is never easy
So you might just be a less bad person
Far from being a terrible person
Far from being a good person
But after that I have a little more respect for myself
Because i also understand
There are some terrible elements in the human mind
You have to respect this
That's a part of yourself
To some extent you have to see yourself as a loaded weapon
When getting along with children
It's very useful to see yourself as a loaded weapon
Because you are a loaded weapon in front of the child
Many children have terrible experiences when they are with their parents
Can confirm this
Anyway, I started to change a bit since then
I really don't know the causality of these things
I guess it’s because I was trying to figure out
Who am i and how to fix this like these
I started paying very close attention to what I said
I don't know if this happened intentionally or unintentionally
But I can feel my heart "split"
Some students told me
They have encountered the same thing
It happened after they heard some of my course materials
I have talked about the information
I split into two so you can say
One is the old one I keep talking
Like arguing like all kinds of ideas
The other part is watching
I just opened my eyes and looked at it neutrally
The me who looked at me neutrally
Observing the me who speaks
Seems to be saying "that's not your idea"
"You don't really believe it"
"You don't understand what you are talking about"
"that is not true"
I thought to myself, "Hoh, that's so funny"
I think so 95% of the time when I speak
Then I really don't know what to do
I thought to myself "Okay, this is weird"
Maybe I split it's not a good thing at all
It’s not that I have auditory hallucinations or something
Not like that
Put it this way, people have many faces
So I encountered this strange puzzle
Which of the two is me
It’s the one who always listens and speaks
"It's rubbish, it's a lie"
"You did that to get people's attention."
"You just want to win the debate"
Is that me
Or it’s me who talks normally
I don't know but i decided i want to be the critic
Then I tried my best to do
Or learn to do
Stop saying those things that make me look vulnerable
I mean I'm still trying to do this
Because I always feel
No matter what I say when I speak
Those words are either helping me find my position
Or it's breaking me up
I do think "calibration"
Is a suitable concept to express it
Because if you express something as honestly as possible
Then they are produced from deep in your heart
We don't know where the ideas come from
We don't know
The idea is to emerge from how deep in your underlying structure
We don’t know what kind of physical calibration you have to go through
To speak from the heart
We don't understand at all
We can't even conceptualize it
But i believe you can feel
I learned something from Carl Rogers
He is an amazing clinician
He thinks mental health
Partly spiritual or abstract
And the body are aligned with each other
In psychoanalysis and clinical thinking
There are many thoughts about calibration
But anyway I decided to start practicing
Don't say the things that make me look weak
The result is
I can't say almost everything I have said
95%, right?
That was a huge blow
It takes months to wake up
Then realized that you were almost a piece of deadwood
This is a heavy hammer
You might think
"Well, do you really want to burn all the deadwood?"
"Well, there is only a little empty shell left."
"Only 5% of you are left."
If that 5% is solid
Then maybe this is exactly what you want
So I said this story is the interpretation of the following verses
"Jehovah sees that people are sinful on earth
"Everything you think about all day long is evil" (Gen 6:5)
This is a question worth asking
"What is your motive?"
Maybe their motives are purer than mine
It is certainly possible
I don't think I was born a particularly good person
I think I have to work very, very hard to do it
I don't think everyone is like that
But some people are worse than that
In a way everyone is so bad
So it's worth thinking about
"How much trouble did you try to cause?"
There is one more thing you can think about
If you are not using your life to do something important
In terms of your own definition
Because that's the game we are participating in
You have to define these terms at least from the beginning
Maybe you get into trouble
But because you didn’t have better things to do
Trouble is more fun than boring
If you read Dostoyevsky, you will understand
Dostoevsky understood this very well
So if you don’t push yourself to the limit
Then you have countless excess will energy and resources
Used to create interesting disasters
I also think this is the prototype scene of this passage
"Jehovah sees that people are sinful on earth
"Everything you think about all day long is evil" (Genesis 6:5)
It's worth thinking about here
That's not self-destructive
Because it's like a diagnosis of a disease
It's like if you are really like that to some extent
May only account for 10% of you may account for 90%
It would be great to be aware of this
Because you may not do it anymore
why not
You obviously have to abandon all your anger and hate these emotions
That's really annoying
Because these emotions are easy to fall into
They are addictive
With a sense of self-righteousness
But you are not doing this to hurt yourself
You are doing this
Leave behind what you don't need
"Jehovah regretted making man on earth
"Sorrow in the heart" (Gen 6:6)
"The Lord says
"'I will create
"『With animals and insects
"『And all the birds in the sky are wiped out from the ground
""I regret it because I made them"" (Genesis 6:7)
What is the main point of this
The theme is that the universe created by God has fallen
It's interesting
This is another point that "Genesis" always poked me
And the facts are true
I told you that Mesopotamians believe
Human beings are made of Jin Gu's blood
He is the worst monster the Chaos Behemoth can imagine
This is a very harsh conclusion
But the reason the Mesopotamians believe so is
They understand as much as the author of Genesis
Human beings are the only ones in the universe
A creature capable of consciously deceiving and doing evil
The question is to what extent
Deliberate deception and evil
Would spoil things so badly
So that they might as well have never existed
You will see stories like this
There is a flood-related story in the Epic of Gilgamesh
Have the same underlying narrative structure
In fact, some people think that Noah’s story comes from this
The gods regretted their creation and made a decision
It is better to clear them than to let them thrive
You will see the same thing in the Mesopotamian creation myth
Early gods in "Enuma Elish"
It can be said to be a representative of "great men on earth"
They made too much noise, too indifferent and sloppy
So Diamat, the original god of creation, and her partner
Determined to purge them from the world
If you read similar text
If you read it from the historical perspective of UBM
It has a depth
Beyond the ancient and fairytale elements of the story itself
I have read some terrible things that happened in Nazi Germany
And what happened when Japan invaded China
Such things are not uncommon in human history
Things will get so bad
It takes the imagination of an extreme villain to conceptualize it
When things are so bad
It can only be described by the words of the most evil person
When I receive visiting customers
Found another thing
When their lives are really not good
When they almost commit suicide or want to kill
Or when something happened at home
It's too corrupt and bad
Those things can be traced back several generations ago
Doomed to misery and destruction
The only language that can describe this situation is religious
Because there is no other language to describe
The seriousness of what happened
Maybe you have never encountered
A situation that requires such seriousness
But that doesn’t mean that situation doesn’t exist
They do exist
You will do everything you can to avoid falling into it
But they do exist
You encounter one or two similar situations at a certain point in your life
This possibility is very high
You will get entangled with someone who is inherently malicious
Maybe the malicious person is you
That would be a huge blow
Then these poetic descriptions become more real
"Only Noah found favor in the sight of the Lord" (Genesis 6:8)
"The descendants of Noah are written below
"Noah is a righteous man
"At the time, I was a perfect person
"Noah walked with God" (Genesis 6:9)
This is an interesting verse
If you remember the story of Adam and Eve
What happened to Adam
When he ate the fruit on the tree of distinguishing good from evil
I woke up with scales falling off my eyes
He has self-awareness and can distinguish good from evil
When God calls him in the garden
He did not walk with God
So Noah is essentially no fallen Adam
Noah did something right
Urge God to forgive him
Or to show him a way through chaos
Something like this
This is worth thinking about
Because you will have this situation in your life
You are facing the chaos that is about to emerge
Maybe it was a terrible disaster in your family
Maybe it happened
The wider social dimension
But chaos is coming
What you will want to know is
Unless you want to be a member of the chaos
Even one of the contributors
Maybe this is what you want
Because in that situation many people would choose
What you want to know is
How to build an Ark to tide over the difficulties
If you are interested in life
If you are interested in an honest being
If you don’t want to cause any unnecessary pain
Then you will want to know
What to do when disaster strikes
So you have ample possibility to get over the difficulties
Restart
When this ancient story is told
"Well, God is not happy, he wants to destroy everything"
Then you better think about it seriously
Then the story goes
"But there is someone who follows another way of being
"So that he survived."
This is worth your serious consideration
You may want to know what the mode of being
Because you might need it
These things are very practical in the deepest sense
They are real in terms of possibility
They are practical in terms of operability
So Noah walked with God
I’m going to jump to the New Testament
I said at the beginning of the lecture series
The Bible is a hyperlinked text
Everything is connected
Reading in order is helpful
But the Bible is not a linear document
The Bible is a
There are countless ways you can
Books to read
you can choose
Countless ways to read it
All text
Are expanding and quoting the rest of the text
I want to jump to the Sermon on the Mount
I think it might be
The most critical text in the New Testament
I think this passage
Most clearly explain
What does it mean to "walk with God"
Then you will be in the ark when the flood comes
This passage is a metaphor for "walking with God"
The most clear presentation of the abstracted concept
If I say you should be like Noah
Walk with God to build the Ark
Obviously this is a poetic and metaphorical suggestion
Difficult to apply in practice
You are very different from the prototype
Not easy to put into practice in your own life
The experience of the archetype must be distinguished and clarified
Make it practical and personal
So you can actually practice it
So I will talk about part of the Sermon on the Mount
The Sermon on the Mount begins with chapter 5 of the Gospel of Matthew
But I won’t talk about the fifth chapter of Matthew
I’ll talk about the end of Chapter 6 of the Gospel of Matthew
And most of Chapter 7
"'How do you want to grow lilies in the wild
""It does not work nor does it spin threads" (Matthew 6:28)
"『But I tell you
"'When Solomon was extremely glorious
"'What he wears is not as good as this flower'" (Matthew 6:29)
"『You little believers
"'The grass in the wild is still today and will be thrown in the furnace tomorrow
""God gave it such a decoration, how about you"" (Matthew 6:30)
"『So don’t worry
"『What to eat and drink
""What to wear"" (Matthew 6:31)
This is a very famous verse
Kind of like a "hippie" Christ
Seems to mean
"Let's do what I want" is an old saying
"Do your own thing and you will lack nothing."
This passage is often interpreted like this
But this is really not a reasonable explanation
Because this command contains implicit conditions
This implicit condition is
"『All the things you need
"'Your Heavenly Father Knows'" (Matthew 6:32)
"'You must first seek his kingdom and his righteousness
""These things will be added to you"" (Matthew 6:33)
This is very different from hippies, right
This is a very interesting point
Must be one of the deepest views I have ever seen
This view is to say
If you set life goals
What you really do
Aiming at the highest good possible
Then what you need
Things that sustain daily life
Will be added to you naturally
This is an assumption but not a simple one
It mainly says
If you have the courage to do the hardest thing you can imagine
Will make your life better than doing other things
So how do you know if this is true
This is what Kierkegaard said
"Leap of Confidence"
Unless you act
Otherwise you can’t know if it’s true
No one can tell you
Because others can work
Of course this is also very interesting
Can others prove that it is equally feasible for you
You must have no reservations in this game
This view is to say
"You must first seek his kingdom and his righteousness" (Matthew 6:33)
When you say don't worry
What to eat and what to wear
This is actually a pretty important warning
This view essentially says
In comparison, the problem of food and clothing is trivial
If you live right in the world
Then most likely you will get these things
I believe this is right
I have observed how people behave in the world
I think
The most effective way to behave is
Conceive the highest good
And then strive to achieve it
If you really know what success is
Then this is success
The most practical way
This is the concept that this sermon wants to convey
It’s like Pinocchio’s story
What happened at the beginning of the Pinocchio story was
Geppetto makes a wish to a star
We have talked a little bit about this
What Geppetto did is
He conceived the highest good
Take this as a benchmark
He made up his mind
Focus on that star
For him, that star is a possible creation
The puppet manipulated by invisible power
Make it autonomous and real
This is really ambitious
We are smart enough to put it in children's movies
But I was too stupid to understand the meaning
This is a very interesting tie
We can know and not know at the same time
When you go to the movies
May think the movie is reasonable
But that doesn’t mean you can go home
I think I must understand the meaning
People are complicated
We exist on different levels
And there is no communication between all these levels
But this movie puts forward a hypothesis that says
The best way to achieve self-realization to make being noble
Is to imagine the best thing possible
And committed to this
Then you might ask yourself
This question is definitely worth asking
"Are there other things worth doing?"
If not then why do you do other things
"『So don’t worry about tomorrow
"'Because tomorrow has its own worries
""One day's difficulties are enough for one day" (Matthew 6:34)
I spent a long time trying to figure out the meaning of this sentence
Because this passage cannot
Simply read as
Is praising grasshoppers and ants
It’s the old fable about grasshoppers and ants
I am not going to tell this fable
But the fable is about ants working and grasshoppers fooling around
In winter, ants live very comfortably
The grasshopper is dead
This passage seems to affirm the grasshopper but it is not
The scripture here is saying something else is saying
If you are heading in the right direction
Focus on your daily work will be effective
I really think it fits
Our understanding of human cognition
The actual situation is
The world will change around your goals
You are a creature with purpose
You must have a goal to act
You are a creature that can aim
You see a point and move towards it
This is born
So you have to have a goal
Assuming your goal is the highest goal
The world around you will be constructed by goals
This goal will build all your knowledge
Also decide what you see and what you can't see
So are your emotions and motivations
So you build yourself around this goal
Then what will happen is
You will encounter a series of challenges and problems in the moment
If you solve the problem properly
Then you will continue to move towards this goal
You can concentrate on the moment
So you can have both fish and bear paws
Because you can point far away
Live in the present at the same time
in my opinion
This will make every moment of the moment full of meaning
If everything you do every day
It's all about the highest goal you can imagine
This is the meaning of sustaining your life
Back to Noah's story
The sky is falling and chaos is coming
If you face such a problem in life
You might want to do something
Really valuable things
Because when the flood floods everything
Something like this can save you from death
Don't you want to wait until the flood comes
Just start to do it
If the ark is only half built and you still can't sail
Then chances are you will drown
"'So, don't worry about tomorrow
"'Because tomorrow has its own worries
""One day's difficulties are enough for one day" (Matthew 6:34)
This is not an optimistic assumption
"'Don't judge people, lest you be judged'" (Matthew 7:1)
"'Because you will be judged just as you judge people
"『What measure do you use to measure
""What measure must be used to measure for you"" (Matthew 7:2)
This is a realistic description
I will not call this passage a suggestion
Because i think this is not a recommendation
This is a description of the structure of reality
It is not the same as the suggestion
What it says is
"What game do you choose to play
"It will be bound by the rules of this game."
This fits perfectly
Our understanding of human psychology
You must be allowed to play the game
Others must be able to cooperate with you during the game
Have to be able to compete with you
You may have some chance
Change the way the game is played
But can you participate in the game
Can't help you decide
You are in the game
You will be bound by the rules of the game
This is how the game works
You better pick one
You are willing to play games that are responsible for the rules
"'Why do you see a thorn in your brother's eye
""But I don't want to have beams in my eyes"" (Matthew 7:3)
"『You have beams in your own eyes
"'How can you tell your brother
"" "Let me remove the thorns from your eyes"" (Matthew 7:4)
You may not know what beam is
A thorn is only as big as a grain of dust
The beam is a big piece of wood
So the problem is not how blind others are
Even if others are more blind than you
The problem described here is
You should care first
"What interferes with your own vision"
You shouldn't interfere with others on such issues
If your mode of being in the world is
You only do things that are helpful to you
Or you think evil and disaster
none of your business
Others need to solve these problems
It's the responsibility of others
Then you won't solve the problem
No matter what you did or did not do
You will stay blind
This won't make things better
So it's best to think like this
"I'm probably blind in many ways
"Maybe there is a way to correct it."
Because you are very likely to be blind in all aspects
In fact it almost must be like this
So think about "Where did I go wrong?"
Would be more helpful
I want to share some things I learned
I learned when arguing with my wife, we often argue
When you start a real discussion with others
You will find that there are many things that cannot be agreed upon
Because you are indeed different creatures
If you want to have a sincere conversation
Will find
The way you look at things is different
You can pretend that this is not the case
Cover up the past
Finally turned into a 30-year cold war
Or you can have a big fight in time
See if we can resolve the contradiction
When we are arguing
Get into this situation from time to time
dilemma
Will also be upgraded to "hate speech"
Ha everyone laughed
Because people know that they are
How many hurtful things have been said
So one thing we learned is
When we are deadlocked
We separate first
Sit down and think about it
"It’s not very happy now."
"We don't know what to do next."
I always think
"Of course it's her fault"
"It's obviously her fault
"At least she has 95% responsibility"
"But maybe I also have 5% responsibility"
I will sit down and think
Then ask myself a question
"Did I do anything in the past six months
"Make this kind of deadlock more likely"
You don't know how fast your brain will
To answer this question
No doubt you did some stupid things
You know in your heart that you remember these things
These things have improved to make you think
Probability of strangling your lover
Then you can tell them these things
Then you can talk
Especially if they did the same thing
You would say "I am such an idiot"
The other person will say "Okay"
"I'm such an idiot too"
Then you two are idiots
Maybe you can talk about it
"『You hypocrites
"『First remove the beam from my eyes
"『Then I can see clearly
""Remove the thorns from your brother's eyes"" (Matthew 7:5)
Hard to disagree with this
"『If you ask, I will give you
"'Look and find
""Knock and open the door for you"" (Matthew 7:7)
"'Because whoever prays will receive
"'He who seeks will find
"'He who knocks will open the door for him'" (Matthew 7:8)
This also sounds very optimistic
But also I think this is a description of the structure of reality
I mean
I observed during clinical treatment
I can see it in my students
People's lives are not what they want
You will ask "Why do you say that?"
Let’s not mention the tragedies and disasters in life
It goes without saying
We do not discuss this issue
Although to varying degrees
Your tragedy was created by you
But I don’t think every bad thing happens to people
Are all deserved results
I think this is a very dangerous premise
Especially because everyone will get sick and die
One of the main reasons why people cannot get what they want
Because I didn’t figure out what I really wanted
You might get something good for you
This may be better than what you want
You may easily get wrong what you want
But you may get something that is really good for you
Why can't you get it
Because you don't try
You didn't think like this
"What if I had this"
I'm not saying
You have to force it by manipulating the world
Dedicated to you something like property or status
That was not what I meant
I'm talking about
Imagine you are taking care of yourself
Like taking care of the person you care about most
Then you think "I am taking care of this person
"I hope the best things happen to this person"
"What does this person's life look like?
"Is it possible?"
People don't do it
People don't sit down and think
"Okay, let's figure it out."
Obviously your life is difficult
After three years you can get what you need
But you have to be careful about this
You can't have everything
You can get what is good for you
But you have to figure out what it is
Then you have to target it
From my experience with people
If they understand what is good
Then target it and finally you can achieve the goal
This is a strange thing
Not that simple
You can have an idea about what is good for you
Then take ten steps in this direction
Then you will find that the planning is a bit wrong
You have to re-plan your goals
You seem to be walking towards the goal like this
But a big reason many people fail is
They never set the standard of success
Because success is a narrow road and not easy to walk through
Your chance of success is zero
So this is a proposition
The proposition is like this
If you really want something
You can have it
The issue is
What is really what you want
The answer is that you have to readjust all aspects of life
Do your best to make this happen
This is the concept of sacrifice, right
Obviously you won't get everything
But maybe you can get what you need
All you have to do is to seek
But seeking is not a whim
Or just today’s wish
You have to take it very seriously
You have to think about it
I want to measure myself
If I want to live correctly in this world
If i want to be a
I think I am more satisfied
I don't mean you have to criticize yourself strictly
So what am I aiming for
I found one thing
You can try
Can test this method
Is a form of prayer
It's like "knocking"
Sit on the bed one day and ask yourself
"I will often do stupid things
"It will definitely mess up my life."
If you really ask
But you must also want to know the answer
This is the real meaning of the question
Can't just talk casually
You have to make sure you want to know the answer
And you will soon find
The answer will shock you
Jung thought about it
He believes that human consciousness can be divided into two polarities
One is the personal consciousness of each of us
The other one he called "self-nature"
You can think of "self" as the inner divinity
This expression is more accurate
This is the universal part of your consciousness that is conscience
It's okay to think so
No matter what your conscience is
You can ask for advice
Similar to Socrates' "Demon"
Socrates said he was different from other beings in ancient Greece
It’s because he would ask his own "Demon" that is his "elf"
He bowed back and asked himself how to behave in the world
Then follow the inner instructions and put it into practice
No matter what the instructions
Socrates did not selfishly demand an answer
He will ask
"I want to show my best self in the world
"I want to do that, what kind of self is that"
You are fully capable of thinking, God knows why
You are also fully capable of imagine
God knows why you are so whimsical
If you bend yourself and ask yourself what is the best ending
Then what will happen
Maybe you will get the answer
This is what it means
"'Who among you has a son asks for bread
""Give him a stone"" (Matthew 7:9)
""If you ask for a fish or give him a snake" (Matthew 7:10)
"『You are not good
"『I know that I can give good things to my children
"'Not to mention your Father in heaven,
""Would you not give more good things to those who beg him"" (Matthew 7:11)
I think this involves the fundamental nature of being
A hypothesis in the New Testament
In a way it is another hypothesis
Different from the one in the structure of the Old Testament
That is, faith makes beings good
This proposal is very interesting
So this concept becomes a behavior-oriented problem
You put the following proposal into practice
I.e. if you behave properly in the world
Being will be presented to you in the form of goodness
But you can only know after putting it into practice
So this is a call
Make you feel "If you behave properly in the world
The proposal of "being will be good" is put into practice
There is no reason to assume the opposite
Assuming its opposite
Will become cynical and full of resentment
It’s not that we have no reason to assume its opposite
It’s not that I can’t understand why people are full of resentment
"'So whatever you want to do with you
"『How do you treat others
"'Because this is the doctrine of the law and the prophets'" (Matthew 7:12)
This is a question of reciprocity, right
This is another experience I learned from Jung
Jung did not interpret this way
This is the so-called "Golden Rule"
Is often understood as "being kind to others"
But this rule does not mean that
Can't even touch the sides
it mean
Let's say in reverse
This will focus the problem on you
Instead of focusing on others to understand
this means
Conceptualize the question of "how to make things good"
If things are good for you
If you are taking care of yourself
Then try to benefit others
This is reflected in Buddhism
Sakyamuni entered Nirvana
The story is like this
Then he was tempted to stay in Nirvana
But he refused and returned to the secular world
Because he felt that it was not enough to reach Nirvana by himself
Let everyone reach Nirvana at the same time
To the effect
Treat yourself right
It's not easy
Because you are depraved and shameless
Cowardly and full of nonsense
An evil and shameful mortal
So it’s not easy, you know it well
It is not easy to treat such a creature correctly
Can't take it for granted
People tend to treat themselves better than others
I don’t think this is obvious at all
But maybe you can start from yourself and tell yourself
"I have to treat myself as if I am worthy"
Then what will it be like
I will apply this thoughtfulness to others later
The assumption here is
If you pass humans
Moral wisdom gained from thousands of hardships
Through evolution and then manifested in various metaphors and stories
And was codified into the written law
Pick out a rule that is above all else
Then it is the principle
This is very interesting
Because it’s saying "this is the law and the prophet"
The law is the rule
But the prophet is the process of rule update
So in a sense the prophet is above the law
So the view of this particular expression is
Efforts to improve their own mode of being
And committed to perfecting the existence of others
This maxim is not just the core of the law
It is also the core of the process of formulating the renewal law
The meaning behind this sentence is very deep
"'You have to enter the narrow gate
"'Because the door to destruction is wide
""The road is big, and there are many people going in"" (Matthew 7:13)
Dare to ask anyone in the world who can argue with it
Anyone who is sober and sane knows
There are thousands of ways to mess things up
There is only one way to do it right, or if you are lucky
So realize the path you take when you are doing the right thing
It’s actually very narrow. This is wisdom.
That is the dividing line between chaos and order
You should always stand on this dividing line
The dividing line is very thin
If you lean slightly to one side
Then there is too much chaos
And lean slightly in the other direction
Then there will be too much order
Neither situation is good
The balance must be just right
You can feel it yourself
I really think you can feel it
This is your deep-rooted instinct
I mean biological instinct
Not a metaphor
I think your mind is to adapt to
Constructed by living in a universe made of chaos and order
I think this is why you have two halves of the brain
This is more profound than metaphor
When you feel yourself
Participate in world time in a meaningful way
When you put aside the fear of death
It's eternity when you put yourself in the world
It’s your innermost instinct that tells you
You are in the right place at the right time
All you have to do is practice repeatedly to be in the present position
That spot is hard to find
You will find it if you are lucky if you wander around that point
You can observe it as an experiment
Observe yourself like a stranger for two weeks
You really don't know yourself
So try to observe yourself for two weeks
You will notice that sometimes things go smoothly
But it’s not easy to notice
Because when everything goes well
You will be obsessed with being unable to pay attention to it
But you will find yourself in the right place
"So how did I come to this place
"What did I do right
"How can we always go smoothly
"I hope it gets better
"How should I act
"It will be smoother in the future."
Then you train
Maybe it’s no longer a month or a week for 10 minutes to observe yourself
But after 15 minutes a day, half an hour a day
Then one hour a day and four hours a day
Then if you are very cautious
Can do it most of the time
"『The way to eternal life is narrow or small
"'There are few people looking for it'" (Matthew 7:14)
"『You must be on guard against false prophets
"'They come to you in sheep's clothing
"'There is a cruel wolf inside'" (Matthew 7:15)
This is a very good suggestion for the current political situation
I can guarantee this
"'You can recognize them by their fruits
"'How can you pick grapes on thorns?
""How can figs be picked from thistles"" (Matthew 7:16)
"'So every good tree bears good fruit
""Only a bad tree bears bad fruit"" (Matthew 7:17)
This is what I learned from
Known in the history of totalitarianism in the 20th century
"Only the bad tree bears bad fruit." That’s for sure
Something interesting
When people think
People will use a primitive and naive way
Think about your relationship with divinity or God
Why can't miracles be revealed
So that I firmly believe in its existence
It’s funny that you won’t just believe it
If the miracle does appear
You will forget it in about half a year
You think you won't forget when the time comes, but you will
You will really forget about it
Because of human nature
But actually catastrophic miracles are happening all the time
This point strengthens my argument
You just won't pay attention
If we cannot learn from the history of the 20th century
Then we are completely incapable of learning
The history of the 20th century is
A collection of hardships and lessons beyond human imagination
The following paragraph can't be described more appropriately
""Bad tree bears bad fruit"" (Matthew 7:17)
""A good tree cannot bear bad fruit
""A bad tree cannot produce good fruit"" (Matthew 7:18)
"'Cut down any tree that doesn't produce good fruit
""Throw in the fire"" (Matthew 7:19)
This is the flood theme
Archetype of the eternal tree
Archetype of being
This is often the prototype of the self
What's the warning here
If you are deadwood
You can easily burn
You can think about it metaphysically
Can be mapped to eternity
Think of it as hell
Interestingly
When it all happens to you in reality
Just like being in eternal hell
Thinking like this makes perfect sense
But you can also remove the metaphysical part
Think of it this way, if you are almost a dead tree
Then it will stop
This is also worth thinking about
"『So with their fruits
""You can recognize them" (Matthew 7:20)
"'Whoever calls me "Lord Lord"
"『You can’t enter heaven
"『Only those who do the will of my Father
""You can get in"" (Matthew 7:21)
I think this sentence is quite interesting
There is such a reasonable critique of traditional Christianity
This is also the criticism given by Nietzsche
That Christianity failed to fulfill its moral mission
Jung is a little more forgiving
I will tell you why later
Nietzsche thinks that traditional Christianity has lost its way
Because it assumes
In a certain ultimate sense, mankind has been saved by the sacrifice of Jesus
This means the work is done
I will make a harsher evaluation now
This is for succinct language
The theme of traditional Christianity is
If you express belief in what has happened
Then you have obtained eternal salvation
The meaning of this layer is not so simple
But I think this is the true meaning of this sentence
This sentence asks "Then how do you enter heaven?"
You can think about this problem from an eternal perspective
Or from a psychological level
Then the answer is very straightforward
Imitate Noah's work to survive the flood
Walk with God
That is the meaning of the admonition
This is the practical development of the admonition
Also set the goal as the highest good
And act in the world
So you might have a chance
The highest form of good inhabiting your being
Maybe no chance
But you can’t think of a more practical way
If you build a house, maybe you can live in it
If you don't build a house
Then can't live in it
If you build a good house
Then you can live in a good house
If you build a perfect house
Then you may live in a perfect house
But if the house has been built for you
You just verbally said that the house has been built for you
Then you can live in a house that meets your needs
The possibility does not exist
"『That day (Judgment Day), many people will say to me
"『Lord, Lord, we didn’t preach in your name
"『“In your name cast out ghosts
""Do you perform many miracles in your name?"" (Matthew 7:22)
"『I told them clearly
"『I never knew you
""You evildoers, leave me"" (Matthew 7:23)
It refers to Judgment Day
That is a prototype concept
Part of the reason it is a prototype is
Every day is judgment day
The logos of you
The ideal part of you
Will always be judged for your sins
It's guilt shame retreat
And the source of resentment, murder and genocide
Because you can intuitively know what is ideal
The problem is
Ideals always exist as judges
There is no difference between the two
So you will never stop being judged by your ideals
If there is no ideal
Then your life has no direction or meaning
Of course the more perfect your ideal, the stricter the judgment
Jung was curious
Why does the Bible add a "Revelation" at the end
Because "Revelation" is a very strange book
Christ in the Gospels
It can be said to be mainly kind
Christianity
The truth and mercy are always at war
Competing between the two, kindness probably prevails
Jung’s observation is that the Christ in the Gospels is too kind
This is also the "Revelation"
Continuing to the reason for the end of the New Testament
Because in "Revelation"
Christ is the transcendent ideal hanging above the pyramid
He is the absolute judge
No one can pass
Of course the ultimate ideal is the ultimate judge
This is its prototype reality
You can say that I don't want to be judged
I don't want to have anything to do with ideals
Then you become Cain
Cain gave up his ideal
But you can't escape
You can't escape the eternal judgment
This is a prototype story
People put a lot of effort into these works
Created hundreds of expressions
They are not jokes
These are serious works
We can't understand
Does not mean those who created these works
Don't know what i'm doing
Those creators are geniuses
Not to say what they mean to themselves
Have precise and clear understanding
But what they are expressing is
Metaphors at the core of our culture
The effect is to make our culture work well and intrinsically good
These metaphors are the foundation of our culture
They are not created for the coward
Some people say that religion is the opium of the people
Then I have a question. How do you explain this?
Because if you are looking for opium
What else does this jury do?
Another interesting thing about this statement is
Look at the "Revelation" and look at the trials
Almost everyone was eventually found guilty
So if some kind of sad desire is to be realized
Then why do you tilt the balance like this
Do you think it will make people feel good
I don't think so
There is almost no picture of the whole picture
Things that make people feel good
If you understand it well
The fear it brings you will touch the depths of your soul
That's the purpose of the picture
"'So anyone who hears me will do it
"『Like a smart person
""Build the house on the rock"" (Matthew 7:24)
"『The rain and the wind blow
"'The house won't collapse when hitting that house
""Because the foundation is on the rock"" (Matthew 7:25)
"'Anyone who hears me and doesn't do it
"『Like an ignorant person
""Build the house on the sand"" (Matthew 7:26)
"『The rain and the wind blow
""Bumping into that house"" (Matthew 7:27)
Oh here is the wrong number
""The house collapsed because the house was built on sand (Matthew 7:27)
This sentence is very interesting
Sometimes you will read certain sentences
Especially in the context of the Bible
You will see words that you can’t believe their real existence
hard to imagine
Someone can come up with such a sentence
I think the following two sentences are good examples
"Jesus finished these words
"Everyone is amazed by his teaching" (Matthew 7:28)
"Because he taught them that they are just like powerful people
"Not like their scribes" (Matthew 7:29)
This is interesting
Because I don’t appreciate it
One of the reasons for those churches I've been to
Those classes are taught by scribes
Talking full of words from the Bible
Without any power
Can't read meaning from it
Like what I did when I was 20
I will say those meaningless words
Those words are just nice
I think those words are like gilded clothing
You can wrap it around
But it doesn’t have any substantial meaning
Something with substantial connotation
And listening to those fancy and fluent things
The difference is huge
This sentence means
Those who say the things we just described
It sounds like someone who knows what he is talking about
Instead of just repeating preaching
Just for those who say beautiful things
in my opinion
These words we just reviewed together
Contains awesome authority influence
Back to Noah
"Only Noah found favor in the sight of the Lord" (Gen 6:8)
"The descendants of Noah are written below
"Noah was a righteous man in the generations he was a perfect man
"Noah walked with God" (Genesis 6:9)
"Noah gave birth to three sons
"It's Shemham Yaphos" (Genesis 6:10)
"The world is corrupted before God
"The ground is full of violence" (Genesis 6:11)
Have you seen the new advertisement of the American Rifle Association
You better check
I think this is what i see
The most shocking manifestation of American political polarization
I have seen a lot of leftists
Most of the people who shocked me most came from the left
But this advertisement really opened my eyes
The ad is voiced by a very attractive woman
She looks a bit like Demi Moore
But she looks fierce
I guess Demi Moore looks fierce sometimes
This lady has a disdain
It is very dangerous
Only the riots about the "anti-fascist movement" in the background
And images of the riot flame protests in Berkeley
She described these as conspiracies
Is a conspiracy involving the intellectual elite
Hollywood was named and named
She accused a group of corrupt intellectuals
Is disintegrating this country
It's time to pick up your guns
You can look at this ad and experience it for yourself
If things go in this direction
Many people will be ecstatic
What i hope is
We can solve this problem in a civilized way
But the current situation is the stupidity of any individual
Can take us one step further from the end
15% or 30% of the population is this kind of people who are afraid of chaos
They will be ecstatic
Because this is their goal
"The world is corrupted before God
"The ground is full of violence" (Genesis 6:11)
"God sees the world is corrupt
"All flesh and blood have corrupted their behavior on earth" (Genesis 6:12)
"God said to Noah
"'The end of anyone who is full of flesh has come to me
"'Because the ground is full of their rape
"'I will destroy them with the earth'" (Genesis 6:13)
"'You have to build an ark out of Gopher wood
"『Build one by one
""Put rosin inside and out"" (Genesis 6:14)
"'This is how the Ark is made
""Three hundred cubits long
""50 cubits wide and 30 cubits high"" (Genesis 6:15)
"'There must be a light-transmitting place on the ark
"『One cubit high
"'The door of the ark must be opened aside
""The Ark shall be divided into three levels: upper, middle and lower" (Genesis 6:16)
"'Look, I will make the flood flood the earth and destroy the world
"'Every living creature with flesh and breath on the earth,
""No one does not die"" (Genesis 6:17)
"'I want to make a covenant with you
"『You and your wife and sons and wives
""All to enter the Ark" (Genesis 6:18)
This is a very optimistic reversal
Noah can save not only himself but the whole family
Shade the descendants
This is a good thing
One of my patients
Her growth experience has been rough
At least I didn’t get a lot of encouragement
But a lot of frustration
She has a son
Speaking of her relationship with her son
It is very interesting
Those misfortunes would have passed on to her son through her
Even though she herself was tortured
Because some people want to make her suffer
But she saved her son from the same treatment
From her pain and suffering
She learned a negative lesson
Just don’t let this behavior pass on
So what I want to express here is
If you are upright, behave reasonably
And walk with God in the way we discussed
Maybe this will not only benefit you alone
And will save your family
It also implies that this might save a society
This is what Noah did
He saved himself and saved his family
But the surrounding area was swept away by the flood
His reasonable behavior saved himself and his family
Also saved the world
It’s interesting that I’ve read a lot about totalitarian disasters
The work of the person who has thought deeply
I think Alexander Solzhenitsyn is second to none
His anthology
A total of 700 pages in three volumes, each page is densely packed
Are calling for
personal
The necessity of personal honesty and integrity
It is the only fortress that can resist the catastrophe of totalitarianism
I have read a lot
The author who wants to find the bane of the 20th century
I think Solzhenitsyn gave
Same conclusion as Victor Frank
Because he experienced the Nazi concentration camp in his early years
I also admire Frank
But Solzhenitsyn brought this topic
Brings another level of depth
And the argument strongly points out
Causes of social deterioration
Every individual in the society becomes corrupt
And the only way to save
Is every individual in the society
Reject corruption within their ability to live
He talked a lot about the people he met in Gulagre
The Gulag here refers to the death camp in the Soviet Union.
This is what he learned
Those people are so strong
Even in the most extreme cases
They will never
Cross the straight and narrow bottom line
The authorities can't do anything about them
Just watching this is enough to change Solzhenitsyn
Of course, after spending some time in the labor camp
He also thought about
"How did I fall into this field?"
Hitler’s fault, Stalin’s fault
Although it is certain that both of them are at fault
But for Solzhenitsyn he felt that he was also at fault
Because he is also in the same game
It’s just a bad game
"'Any living creature with flesh and blood
"『Two each, one male and one female
"『You have to bring into the Ark
""Fortunately to save life from you"" (Genesis 6:19)
Another message in the story is
Dependent on Noah’s correct behavior
Not only him and his family and human society
But the creatures of the whole earth
Take the limitlessly and use the extreme
And the era of widespread hypocrisy
This is something worth thinking about
Maybe this is the best behavior for everything
Including for those things outside the boundaries of human society
To regulate one's own behavior
From the smallest micro level to the final macro level
Regulate yourself in all dimensions of your being
This is the salvation of all beings
This is the main point of this story
As a cynical modern person
We are interpreting it like a primitive man
Only primitive people will believe
Someone can build a boat and bring two for each species
So we can save the world
Any work is interpreted so superficially
Are unbearable
Especially those who cannot use ignorance as an excuse
These stories are for everyone to see, right
There are many people in the world who are not very smart
So they like to understand things rigidly
Just like how your child understands when you read a story book to your child
This story can be understood rigidly
Because this story is for everyone
But if you are mature enough
You shouldn’t understand it in a child’s way
Maybe you have an obligation to dig deeper meanings
Then think about
If this story is only what the fool sees
If there is no deeper connotation
It will not spread for thousands of years
"'You have to save up all kinds of food
""Good food for you and them"" (Genesis 6:21)
"Noah just did it
"Everything God orders
"He did the same" (Gen 6:22)
"The Lord said to Noah
"『You and your whole family will enter the Ark
"『Because in this generation
""I see you are righteous before me"" (Genesis 7:1)
"'All clean animals you have to bring seven males and seven females
""Unclean animals, you have to bring a male and a female" (Gen 7:2)
"'The flying birds in the sky also have seven males and seven females
""You can keep the seeds and live on the whole earth"" (Gen 7:3)
"『Because in another seven days,
"'I will rain on the earth forty days and forty nights,
"『The various living creatures I made
""All are destroyed from the earth"" (Gen 7:4)
"Noah did what the Lord commanded" (Gen 7:5)
"When the flood hits the ground
"Noah was six hundred years old" (Gen 7:6)
"Noah and his wife and sons and wives
"All went into the ark to avoid the flood" (Gen 7:7)
"Clean animals and unclean animals
"Birds and all insects on the ground" (Gen 7:8)
"It’s all one-on-one with a male and a female
"Go to Noah and enter the ark
"As God commanded Noah" (Genesis 7:9)
"After those seven days
"The flood flooded the ground" (Gen 7:10)
"When Noah was six hundred years old
"The day of February 17
"The source of the Great Abyss is cracked
"The windows of heaven are also opened" (Gen 7:11)
"Heavy rain fell on the earth forty days and nights" (Gen 7:12)
"On that day Noah and his three sons, Shemham Yaphos
"And Noah's wife and three children
"All entered the Ark" (Gen 7:13)
"They and the beasts follow each other
"All livestock follow their kind
"Insects crawling on the ground follow their own kind
"All birds follow their kind
"All into the Ark" (Gen 7:14)
"Any living creature with flesh and breath
"Go to Noah and enter the ark one by one" (Gen 7:15)
This makes Noah the ultimate shepherd
The guardian of the garden, the caretaker of everything
This is really an important role
Maybe this job saved him from flooding
"Everyone who enters the ark with flesh and blood has a male and a female
"As God told Noah
"The Lord shut him in the ark" (Gen 7:16)
"Flood flooded the ground for forty days
"The water goes up
"Floating the Ark from the Ground" (Gen 7:17)
"The water is rising greatly on the ground" (Gen 7:18)
"The water is fifteen cubits higher than the mountain
"The mountains are submerged" (Genesis 7:20)
"Every animal that has flesh and blood on the ground
"It's birds and livestock
"Animals and insects crawling on the ground
"And all people are dead" (Genesis 7:21)
"Where on the dry land
"All creatures with breath in their nostrils are dead" (Genesis 7:22)
"All kinds of living things on the earth,
"With people, livestock, insects, and birds in the sky
"All wiped out from the ground
"Leave only Noah and those who were with him in the ark" (Gen. 7:23)
"The water is on the earth for a total of 150 days." (Gen. 7:24)
"God remembers Noah
"With all the animals and livestock in Noah's Ark
"God made the wind blow the ground and the water gradually fell" (Genesis 8:1)
"The windows of Yuanyuan and the sky are closed
"The heavy rain in the sky stopped" (Gen. 8:2)
"The water recedes from the ground
"After one hundred and fifty days, the water fades away" (Gen. 8:3)
"July 17
"The Ark rests on Mount Ararat" (Genesis 8:4)
"The water fades again
"By the first day of October
"The top of the mountain has appeared" (Genesis 8:5)
"Forty days have passed
"Noah opened the window of the ark" (Genesis 8:6)
"Release a crow
"The crow flies around
"Until the water on the ground dries up" (Gen. 8:7)
"He released another pigeon
"We have to see if the water has receded from the ground" (Genesis 8:8)
"But there is water everywhere
"The pigeon can't find a place to stay
"Just go back to Noah Ark
"Noah reached out and took the dove into the ark" (Gen. 8:9)
"He waited for another seven days
"Release the dove from the ark" (Genesis 8:10)
"At night the pigeon returns to him
"With a freshly twisted olive leaf in my mouth
"Noah knew that the water on the earth had receded" (Genesis 8:11)
"He waited for another seven days
"Release the pigeons
"The pigeons will never come back" (Genesis 8:12)
"When Noah was 601 years old
"The first day of the first month
"The water on the ground is dry
"Noah removed the cover of the ark to watch
"I saw it dry on the ground" (Genesis 8:13)
"It's February 27th
"The land is dry" (Genesis 8:14)
"God said to Noah" (Genesis 8:15)
"『You and your wife, son and wife
""Everyone can go out of the Ark" (Genesis 8:16)
"『Every living thing with flesh and blood in your place
"『It’s the birds and livestock
"『And all the insects crawling on the ground
"'Bring it out and let it breed on the ground
""Great Prosperity" (Genesis 8:17)
"So Noah and his wife, sons and wives
"All came out" (Genesis 8:18)
"All animals, insects and birds
"And all the animals on the ground
"Everyone in his own way also came out of the ark" (Genesis 8:19)
"Noah built an altar for the Lord
"Take all kinds of clean livestock and birds
"On the altar as a burnt offering" (Genesis 8:20)
This immediately returns to the subject of sacrifice
"The Lord smells that sweet fragrance" (Genesis 8:21)
This is Noah's right sacrifice
"Just say in my heart
"'I no longer curse the land for people's sake
"『People have evil thoughts from their childhood
"『Don’t press me anymore
""All living creatures are destroyed" (Genesis 8:21)
"While the earth still remains
"Jiazhen, winter and summer
"Day and night will never stop" (Genesis 8:22)
"God blessed Noah and his son
"Tell them
""You must be fruitful and multiply and fill the earth" (Genesis 9:1)
"'The beasts on the earth and the birds in the sky
"'I will be frightened and afraid of you
"'Even all the insects on the ground and all the fish in the sea
""Hands over to you"" (Genesis 9:2)
I have heard of critics
For example, David Suzuki
Claims to be the substructure of Western civilization
As shown in the text above
Is sending the earth into human hands
And is justifying our abuse of being
I think this interpretation is not cautious
I think such an important thing
It is necessary to interpret with a more cautious attitude
In the story of Adam and Eve
When Adam and Eve were driven out of Paradise
God says she will obey her husband
He didn't say this should happen
What he said is this will happen
I think in these words
Have the same meaning
This event may not have happened
It has happened
It’s hard to imagine how long ago these words were written
It was not obvious until the 1960s
We completely control the earth
So that we have the future in our hands
This reflects the prophetic element in this story
"'The beasts on the earth and the birds in the sky
"'I will be frightened and afraid of you
"'Even all the insects on the ground and all the fish in the sea
""Hands over to you"" (Genesis 9:2)
That’s how it became reality
"'Any living animal can be your food
"『I give you all this
""Like vegetables" (Genesis 9:3)
"'Only flesh with blood is its life
""You must not eat"" (Genesis 9:4)
"'Blood you to kill you
""Whether it is a beast or a human, I will punish him
"'Even to everyone's brothers'" (Genesis 9:5)
This chapter is difficult to interpret
Its meaning is like this
God explains the reborn human
Have master of the earth
And enumerate the power to dominate
Then draw a line of power
The limit is no matter how big the authority is
Should keep the dignity of life
Although it’s difficult to extract this meaning from an article translated this way
What God wants to tell Noah is
If you kill yourself and kill others
If animals kill humans
Have to pay the price
So there is such a possibility
Noah’s descendants can dominate the earth
Moral boundary
I.e. anyway
Life itself should be regarded as sacred and dignified
"'Anyone who sheds blood will also be shed
"'Because God created man in His own image'" (Genesis 9:6)
"『You have to bear and grow many
""Prosperity on the earth" (Genesis 9:7)
"God spoke to Noah and his sons" (Genesis 9:8)
""I make a covenant with you and your descendants"" (Genesis 9:9)
"『And with all the living creatures here
"'It's birds, livestock, and beasts
""All living creatures that come out of the ark make a covenant" (Genesis 9:10)
"『I make a covenant with you
"'All flesh and blood will no longer be extinct by the flood
""There will be no more floods destroying the land" (Gen 9:11)
"God said
"『I and you
"『And the eternal covenant made by all the living creatures here
""It is marked"" (Genesis 9:12)
"『I put the rainbow in the clouds
""This can be a sign of my covenant with the earth"" (Genesis 9:13)
"『When I made the clouds cover the ground
""There must be a rainbow now in the clouds" (Genesis 9:14)
"『I will remember
"『My covenant with you and all living creatures
"『The water will never overflow
""Destroy all flesh and blood"" (Genesis 9:15)
Here is an agreement similar to negotiation
This negotiated agreement
In my opinion
If humans agree to be upright like Noah
The threat of catastrophic destruction will not come
"'The rainbow must now be in the clouds
"'I will remember when I see it
"『I and every living creature on the earth
""The Eternal Covenant" (Genesis 9:16)
"God said to Noah
"『This is me and the earth
"'All flesh and blood have made the sign of the covenant'" (Genesis 9:17)
Let's come to an end here
By the way, there will be no lectures next week
Because the theater was booked
So let's take a week off
We will finish Noah’s story when we come back
Not much left
Then we will talk about the story of the Tower of Babel
Is a short but interesting story
Then we will tell the story of Abraham
Thank you for coming. See you in two weeks